A Guide to the Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial records, Audiovisual materials, Series 39 FA756
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Nelson A. Rockefeller, Political Films, 1945-1976; 1
  - 1970
    - 1970 Rockefeller Campaign Commercials (Reel AV 1837)
      Compilation reel of tv spots from NAR 1970 gubernatorial campaign; 25 different commercials including issues about budget, SUNY system extension, importance of growing businesses, limiting taxes, drug policies, etc.
    - Annual Message to the Legislature, 1970 January 7 (Reel III 14.1 Fg 32, Reel III 14.1 Fg 31)
    - Bob Hope Dinner with NAR, 1970 March 20 (Reel AV 1575)
      From NBC-TV.
      III 14.1 Fb 15
    - 1970 Miss Universe Parade, 1970 August 8 (Reel AV 1248)
      UPI News footage of NAR hosting Marisol Malaret, Miss Universe 1970, in New York City at a parade and a luncheon.
      III 14.1 Fa 97
    - Hudson Highlands State Park Dedication, 1970 May (Reel AV 3.16, Box 1, Dvd AV 3.16)
      footage from 1970 May ceremony with speeches by Governor NAR and Laurance Rockefeller
      III 14.1 Fg 34
    - Election Night Coverage, 1970 November 3 (Reel AV 1250, Box 2, Dvd AV 1250)
      NBC coverage of NAR at the Roosevelt Hotel in NYC.
      III 14.1 Fa 99
  - 1971-1976
    - Governor Rockefeller at Joint Session of Legislature Opening Day, 1971 January 6 (Box 2, Dvd AV 1389, Reel AV 1389)
      close-up shots from speech
      III 14.1 Fe 27
    - NAR Inauguration, 1971 January 1 (Reel AV 1757, Box 1, Dvd AV 3.17)
      Footage from inauguration in Albany, NY
      III 14.1 Ff 30
    - Governor Rockefeller Nominates Richard Nixon, 1972 August (Box 2, Dvd AV 1383, Reel AV 1686)
      NAR nominates Nixon as presidential candidate at Republican National Convention in Miami.
      III 14.1 Fd 47
    - Annual Message to the Legislature, 1973 January 3 (Reel AV 1774, Reel AV 1816)
      Footage of Governor NAR annual message to the New York State Legislature, filmed in the Assembly Chamber at the Capital Building in Albany, NY.
    - NAR Press Conference on Drugs, 1973 January 22 (Reel AV 1078)
      Press conference with Governor NAR, Rev. Oberia D. Dempsey, Rev. Earl B. Moore, Glester Hinds, Dr. George W. McMurray, and Dr. Robert W. Baird.
      III 14.1 Ff 33
    - George Washington Inauguration Day Ceremony, 1976 April 30 (Reel AV 1096)
      Footage of speech by Vice President NAR at reenactment festivities.
      III 14.1 Fb 21
    - The View From the Bottom (Reel AV 1074)
      Collection of interviews about social welfare and urban programs coordinated by NAR.
      III 14.1 Ff 47
- Nelson A. Rockefeller, Political Video material, 1960-1975; 2
  No current arrangement by an archivist.
  - Election Eve: Wrap-Up!, 1962 November 5; Sound, Black and white, 30 minutes; 2 inch videotape (Reel AV 10596)
    Access copy available.
    Post-election roundtable discussionk with the Rockefeller team summarizing the entire campaign, including: Marcus G. Christ, John P. Lomenzo, Louis J. Lefkowitz, Malcolm Wilson, Jacob K. Javits, and Nelson A. Rockefeller.
  - 1964 California Primary, 'The Extremists', 1964 May 27; Sound, Black and white, 30 minutes; 2 inch videotape (Reel AV 10597)
    Program features Governor Nelson A. Rockefeller, Dave Garroway, and others discussing the efforts of right-wing extremists to influence and/or control the California Republican State Party.
  - Executive Chamber, Number 1: How Much Education?, November 1964; Sound, Black and white, 30 minutes; 2 inch videotape (Reel AV 10603)
    New York State Governor Nelson A. Rockefeller and education professionals discusses the need for education and the state of the New York State schools.
  - Executive Chamber, Number 3: In The Name of the People, 1964 December; Sound, Black and white, 30 minutes; 2 inch videotape (Reel AV 10637)
    In his annual message to the legislature, Governor Nelson A. Rockefeller recommends solutions to the problems facing the people of New York State. These include: issues of education on all levels, water pollution abatement, per capita aid, traffic safety, and full crew law. The Governor also relates how state laws are made.
  - Executive Chamber, Number 4: The View from the Governor's Chair, 1965 January 26; Sound, Black and white, 30 minutes; 2 inch videotape (Reel AV 10635)
    New York State Governor Nelson A. Rockefeller reports in detail about the New York State annual budget. Several key figures speak about their requested funding including: Dr. William J. Ronan from the Tri-State Transportation Committee, Lawrence W. Pierce from the Division of Youth, J. Burch McMorran, Supt. of Public Works, George K. Wyman, Commissioner of Social Welfare, John Hathorn from the Office of Indian Affairs, Dr. James E. Allen, Commissioner of Education, and Dr. Henry Brill, Director of Pilgrim State Hospital. Captain John C. Miller of the Oneida Barracks N.Y. State Police requests a $150 increase for dog food.
  - Executive Chamber, Number 6: Transportation Tangle, 1965 March; Sound, Black and white, 30 minutes; 2 inch videotape (Reel AV 10599)
    New York State Governor Nelson A. Rockefeller discusses the creation of the Metropolitan Transportation Authority (MTA) and the Federal Department of Transportation.
  - Executive Chamber, Number 7: Troubled Mind, 1965 April; Sound, Black and white, 30 minutes; 2 inch videotape (Reel AV 10600)
    New York State Governor Nelson A. Rockefeller and health professionals discusses mental illness, the need to create new facilities, and the progress of New York State hospitals.
  - Oregon Campaign - Citizens' Questions and Answers, 1964; Sound, Black and white, 38 minutes; 2 inch videotape (Reel AV 10601)
    Oregon citizens meet one-on-one with Nelson A. Rockefeller in an outdoor forum to ask their questions.
  - Pre-Convention Legislative Reports I, 1962 April 23; Sound, Black and white, 30 minutes; 2 inch videotape (Reel AV 10602)
    Compilation reel with Governor Nelson A. Rockefeller reporting on recent New York State legislative actions, includings economic growth, housing, education, law enforcement, among others. Each segment is approximately 3 minutes in duration.
  - Pre-Convention Legislative Reports II, 1962 October; Sound, Black and white, 55 minutes; 2 inch videotape (Reel AV 10636)
    Compilation reel with Governor Nelson A. Rockefeller and his campaign team reporting on recent New York State legislative actions.
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
    Program begins with 4 minutes of black. Intermittent black between segments.
  - Inauguration 1967, Assembly Room Speeches, 1967 January 2; Sound, Black and white, 30 minutes; 2 inch videotape (Reel AV 10604)
    From the Capitol Building in Albany, the inaugeration of Nelson A. Rockefeller in his third term as Governor of New York state.
  - Governor Rockefeller's Special News Conference on Narcotics, 1973 January 22; Sound, Color, 30 minutes; 2 inch videotape (Reel AV 10605)
    Governor Nelson A. Rockefeller's January 23, 1973 press conference in Albany, New York regarding the drug problem in New York state. Speakers include: Reverend Oberia D. Dempsey, Reverend Earl B. Moore, Glester Hinds, Dr. George W. McMurray, and Dr. Robert W. Baird. A question and answer session with the press concludes the programs.
    The video begins with 40 seconds of color bars and tones.
  - Four Stars on the Issues, 1960 October 19; Sound, Black and white, 185 minutes; 2 inch videotape (Reel AV 10606)
    Discussion with Vice President Richard Nixon, New YorkY State Govenor Nelson A. Rockefeller, and New York Senators Jacob K. Javits and Kenneth B. Keating on the issues New York citizens have stated are important to them in this election. CBS Production # 10-2785-1019
    Unedited videotape. First 2:30 minutes no image, low volume. Program begins at 3:20.
  - Governor Rockefeller Reviews the 1965 Legislature, 1965 June 24; Sound, Black and white, 15 minutes; 2 inch videotape (Reel AV 10608)
    Begins with 1 minute of NBC test pattern and tones. Image quality poor. Image progressively gets worse throughout duration of tape.
    Govenor Nelson A. Rockefeller gives his opinions about what has transpired in the New York state capitol during the 1965 Legislative session.
  - Godkin Lectures Number 1: The Future of Federalism, Part 1, 1962 February 7; Sound, Black and white, 50 minutes; 2 inch videotape (Reel AV 10643)
    Governor Nelson A. Rockefeller presents the first of three lectures on 'The Future of Federalism' as part of the Godkin Lecture Series at Harvard University.
    Program begins at 2:40.
  - Godkin Lectures Number 1: The Future of Federalism, Part 2, 1962 February 7; Sound, Black and white, 14 minutes; 2 inch videotape (Reel AV 10645)
    Program begins at 2:14.
  - Godkin Lectures Number 2: The Future of Federalism, Part 1, 1962 February 8; Sound, Black and white, 35 minutes; 2 inch videotape (Reel AV 10610)
    Image is black for last minute of recording, audio only.
    Governor Nelson A. Rockefeller presents the second of three lectures on 'The Future of Federalism' as part of the Godkin Lecture Series at Harvard University.
  - Godkin Lectures Number 2: The Future of Federalism, Part 2, 1962 February 8; Sound, Black and white, 30 minutes; 2 inch videotape (Reel AV 10611)
  - Godkin Lectures Number 3: The Future of Federalism, Part 1, 1962 February 8; Sound, Black and white, 45 minutes; 2 inch videotape (Reel AV 10644)
    Governor Nelson A. Rockefeller presents the third of three lectures on 'The Future of Federalism' as part of the Godkin Lecture Series at Harvard University.
  - Godkin Lectures Number 3: The Future of Federalism, Part 2, 1962 February 8; Sound, Black and white, 50 minutes; 2 inch videotape (Reel AV 10612)
  - 1964 California Republican Presidential Primary: Report to Rockefeller, Sound, Black and white, 30 minutes; 2 inch videotape (Reel AV 10613)
    Governor Nelson A. Rockefeller presents his views on the issues of interest and concern to the Republican voters of California. He is joined by Senator John McCarthy, Assemblyman Milton Marks, Assembly man John Veneman, Assemblyman George Milias, and Assemblyman William Bagley.
  - Thomas E. Dewey Talks About Governor Nelson Rockefeller, 1966; Sound, Black and white, 165 minutes; 2 inch videotape (Reel AV 10614)
    Silent footage at beginning. Program begins at 1 minute 40 seconds.
    From the Cotillion Room at the Sheraton Hotel in Rochester, New York, the former three term governor of New York State, Thomas E. Dewey, encourages Republicans to vote to re-elect Nelson Rockefeller.
  - Governor Nelson A. Rockefeller Message to the Legislature, 1969 January 8; Sound, Color, 47 minutes; 2 inch videotape (Reel AV 10615)
    Tape begins with 1 minute of color bars and tones, followed by approximately 17 minutes of unedited footage from the Assemby Chamber in the New York state capitol building.
    Governor Rockefeller presents his annual message to the New York Legislature. This is his eleventh such appearance.
  - Breakfast with the Long Island Association, 1969 August 7; Sound, Black and white, 1 hour, 42 minutes; 2 inch videotape (Reel AV 10616)
    From Georgian Room of the Garden City Hotel, Governor Nelson A. Rockefeller speaks to members of the Long Island Association of Commerce and Industry about the Long Island Railroad.
  - Senator's Report, 1975 February 25; Sound, Color, 30 minutes; 2 inch videotape (Reel AV 10617)
    From Washington, a report to Pennsylvania from the U.S. Senate by Senator Hugh Scott. Scott answers questions from his three guests from the press.
  - Governor Nelson A. Rockefeller Press Conference: Resignation as Governor of New York, 1973 December 11; Sound, Color, 35 minutes; 2 inch videotape (Reel AV 10618)
    Excerpts from a press conference where Governor Nelson A. Rockefeller discusses his resignation as New York state governor. Event takes place in the Red Room of the state capital.
  - Governor Nelson Rockefeller: "Today Show" Segment on New York State Drug Laws, 1973 September 7; Sound, Color, 17 minutes; 2 inch videotape (Reel AV 10619)
    Governor Rockefeller's appearance on the Today Show where he discusses newly implemented drugs laws with host Barbara Walters.
  - The Governor's Annual Message to the Legislature, 1967 January 4; Sound, Black and white, 30 minutes; 2 inch videotape (Reel AV 10620)
    Governor Nelson Rockefeller addresses the opening session of the 1967 New York state legislature, also known as the State of the State Message.
  - Victory Vanguard - 1962 Campaign, Sound, Black and white, 30 minutes; 2 inch videotape (Reel AV 10621)
    Episode of Victory Vanguard that looks at the 1962 state election, with Governor Nelson A. Rockefeller. Program sponsored by the New York Republican State Committee.
  - Governor Nelson Rockefeller on Liquor Law Reform, 1964 April 9; Sound, Black and white, 13 minutes; 2 inch videotape (Reel AV 10622)
    Governor Nelson Rockefeller discusses liquor law reform after corruption occurs in New York State. Program presented and paid for by N.Y. State Citizens Committee for Liquor Reform. Air date: 1964 April 11.
  - Governor Nelson A. Rockefeller's State of the State Address to the 1966 New York State Legislature, 1966 January 5; Sound, Black and white, 32 minutes (Reel AV 10623)
    Other Finding Aids
    2 inch videotape
    Program begins with 1 minute of bars and tones.
    Separated Materials
    A joint session of the New York State Assembly and Senate for the purpose of receiving the annual message of the Governor.
  - Senator Jits Nominating Speech, 1966 September 9; Sound, Black and white, 21 minutes; 2 inch videotape (Reel AV 10624)
    No sound until 1:30. Program begins at 3 minutes.
    From the the 1966 New York State Republican Convention, Nelson A Rockefeller is nominated for Governor. Unedited footage at beginning of tape.
  - Oregon Campaign Film, 1964; Sound, Black and white, 26 minutes; 2 inch videotape (Reel AV 10625)
    Film with Nelson A. Rockefeller and Happy Rockefeller campaigning in Oregon.
    Contains silent footage at end of program.
  - Nelson and Winthrop Rockefeller Nominating Segments, 1968 August; Sound, Color, 51 minutes; 2 inch videotape (Reel AV 10626)
    Access copy available
    From the 1968 Republican National Convention, Gerald Ford introduces Governor Raymond P. Shafer who nominates Nelson A. Rockefeller for Republican candidate for President. Rockefeller speaks. Also speaking: Winthrop Rockefeller, and others.
    Program has intermittent sections where picture goes to black.
  - The Man Who Can, 1968 July 16; Sound, Color, 1 hour; 2 inch videotape (Reel AV 10631)
    Film documenting Nelson A. Rockefeller's 1968 run for President. Program aired on NBC-TV.
  - Gov. Nelson Rockefeller's Declaration of Non-Candidacy in the 1968 Primaries, Sound, Color, 35 minutes; 2 inch videotape (Reel AV 10630)
    Begins with one minute of color bars and tones.
    Press conference with Nelson Rockefeller reiterating that he is not a candidate campaigning directly or indirectly for the presidency of the United States.